Preeti Chachlani

1200 E Hillsdale Blvd. Foster City California 94404 • LinkedIn • (641) 781-0922 • Github • pchachlani1@gmail.com

CAREER PROFILE

Analyst with an MBA and MA Economics (Quantitative Methods +Health Policy). Worked in the banking industry for 8 years before making a switch to healthcare domain. Have been working as a data analyst in education and healthcare domains for almost 2 year.

SKILLS

SAS, R, Stata, SAS Viya, MS-Excel

EXPERIENCE

The Sphere Institute, California

Data and Policy Analyst, 11/2019-10/2020

- Conducted data investigations and statistical analyses for CMS utilizing SAS
- Manipulated and summarized Medicare Parts A, B and D claims data to produce statistical results
- Wrote flexible SAS macros and generated reports
- Created Excel workbooks/ PowerPoints/word documents to interpret and present the results of the investigations
- Created visual dashboards using SAS Viya
- Maintained data dictionary and metadata

Georgia Department of Early Care & Learning, Georgia

Data Analyst Intern, 01/2019-05/2019

- Modeled data using advanced excel functions: VLOOKUPS, Pivots, Advanced Charting and Excel Macros
- Translated data into key performance metrics, created figures in Tableau and presented in PowerPoint
- Researched and responded to daily quantitative research inquiries from the policy team
- Used VBA to create a macro that can easily calculate and format the routine daily and monthly reports

Georgia State University, Georgia

Graduate Research Assistant, 08/2017-05/2019

Research Paper, Effects of the ACA Medicaid on self-reported Health Outcomes

- Analyzed results of public surveys, such as the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS), with an eye toward ACA Medicaid expansion impacts on self-reported health in the past 7 years
- Used Stata for cleaning the BRFSS data and implemented difference-in-difference model for analysis

Multiple Regression Models in Stata

Used datasets from Botswana's 1988 Demographic and Health Survey to research on changes in fertility rates due to education

Data Mining Project

- Implemented logistic regression techniques on 284,000 observations to predict likelihood of car accident fatalities
- Curated data to conduct exploratory data analysis, cleaning, and pre-model analysis in SAS.

State Bank of India

Credit Manager, Team Lead, Corporate Lending, 01/2009-07/2017

- Appraised and recommended quantum and mix of credit facilities (Loans and Guarantees) for Small and Medium Enterprise clients (mostly family businesses with annual revenues 10M 60M USD)
- Achieved profit CAGR of 43.56% during 2014-17 through effective pricing, adding new products, and new clients
- Got fast track promotion to the Middle Management Grade by outscoring >1000 officers at equivalent grade in an academic exam

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Economics (Quantitative Methods)

Georgia State University

Master of Business Administration, Finance and Marketing

Faculty of Management Studies, Maharishi Dayanand Saraswati University

Bachelor of Arts, Economics (Honors) and Mathematics

Sophia College

AWARDS

• The Mark E. Schaefer Economics Award, Georgia State University

• Outstanding Graduate Student Award, Georgia State University

May 2019 GPA 4.15/4.30

June 2009

GPA: 4.0/4.0

31 A. T.0/T.0

May 2007 GPA: 4.0/4.0

April 2019 December 2018